Ten Artem

Backend Software Engineer

artemtenchik@gmail.com

+7 985 051 08 50

Uzbekistan, Tashkent

Visa sponsorship required

I am an inspired Software Engineer and Tech Lead with over eight years of experience. Have a bachelor degree in computer science, thus it was my conscious decision to tie my life with IT. Experienced in development and operations in startups and product companies. Also led a team of three software engineers. Took part in developing architecture, low-level design, code reviews and knowledge sharing. Owned the successful delivery of the end-to-end project lifecycle

SKILLS

Spoken Languages Russian (Native), English (Upper Intermediate)

Programming Languages Go, PHP

Relational databases Mysql, Postgres, MSSQL

NoSQL Reddis, Memcached, Couchbase, Tarantool

Observability Prometheus, Grafana, Kibana, Sentry, Elastic APM

Infrastructure Docker, Kubernetes, Nomad, GitLab, CI/CD

API GRPC, Rest (Swagger)
Message brokers Kafka, RabbitMQ
Full-text search Elasticsearch

WORK EXPERIENCE

TSUM Moscow Senior Backend Software Engineer - Core Services	Moscow, Russia September 2021 – Jun 2023
Citilink.ru	Moscow, Russia
Tech Lead/ Senior Software engineer	Sep 2019 – Sep 2021
Glavdostavka.ru	Moscow, Russia
PHP software engineer	Sep 2017 – Aug 2021
Beontop.ru	Kovrov, Russia
Full Stack developer	Jul 2016 – Aug 2017
Vseinstrumenti.ru	Kovrov, Russia
Junior PHP software engineer	Jun 2015 – Jul 2016

EDUCATION

Kovrov State Technological AcademyKovrov, RussiaEconomics and Business Management2015 - 2017

Kovrov State Technological AcademyKovrov, RussiaComputer Science2011 - 2015

Work Experience

Most Relevant Projects

Project 1: Online marketplace – core services

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Developed a set of services that helped to launch brand new marketplace that increased company's revenue:
 - 1. A group of services responsible for delivering messages to clients (sms, push, email)
 - 2. Service for searching items via Elasticsearch
 - 3. Stock keeping unit service responsible for managing marketplace items
- Implemented a set of tools that increased reliability and availability of services and speed of development:
 - 1. Feature-toggle service and package responsible for changing background workers without service redeployment
 - 2. Package implementing outbox pattern for reliable message sending through message brokers
 - 3. Client for Kafka that allowed to retry message processing if error occurred
 - 4. Server interceptors that helped to observe services metrics and logs

KEY RESPONSIBILITIES

- Design, develop and implement software that improves the stability, scalability, availability and latency of the services.
- Solve problems occurring with highly available production systems and build solutions and automation to prevent them from happening again.
- Take ownership of multiple services
- Build effective monitoring to monitor the health of the system, and jump in to handle outages.
- Build and run capacity tests to manage the growth of your systems.
- Interaction with the stakeholders (holding meetings, collecting requirements).

Project 2: Payment system in online and offline stores

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Designed and implemented complex offline payment system responsible for payment via bank terminals in offline stores that helped business to automate payment process and remove cashiers
- Designed reliable payment workflow with BPMN
- Integrated Business Process Management System Camunda that ran aforementioned payment workflow orchestrating business process and aborting payment and refunding money if critical error occurs
- Developed a group of services responsible for payment process:
 - 1. Service that manages payment process on bank terminal
 - 2. Tax service that interacts with third party API and applies tax information to invoice
 - 3. Payment management service that interacts with internal ERP system and applies payment data
- Developed and launched website online payment service that added new payment methods and improved clients payment experience

KEY RESPONSIBILITIES

- Lead a team of three software engineers
- Develop new and refine existing services to provide more availability and reliability
- Make long term technical decisions
- Wright technical documentation
- Enforce coding standards and best practices